Contact

pradeep122@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pradeep122 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Scala

Java8

DevOps

Languages

English

Telugu

Hindi

Honors-Awards

Prathibha Award

Publications

Towards Controlled Natural Language for Semantic Annotation

Engineering a Controlled Natural Language into Semantic MediaWiki

A Use case for Controlled Languages in Ontology based Knowledge Management

HMM-based Language-independent POS Tagger

On Designing Controlled Natural Languages for Semantic Annotation

Pradeep Varma

Software Architect and Team Lead with an interest in Security, Distributed Systems and Scalability

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Summary

Pradeep Dantuluri is the Lead Engeneer and Architect at Yantranet. As an early hire, he built the core development team in India ground up. He was instrumental in building the YantraPlatform and the suite of products that work seamlessly on top of it. He is a techie at heart with a dose of entrepreneurial spirit, co-founded a couple of startups, InMins and Tickscore, before joining Srihari at Yantranet. He has a BTech from IIIT Allahabad and worked 3 years as a Semantic Web Researcher in DERI, Ireland

Experience

Yantranet Inc Lead Engineer and Architect April 2012 - Present

Hyderabad Area, India

- Yantranet is a fully bootstrapped company, and have been cash-flow positive since day one. We are a part of NASSCOM 10K incubator and XLR8 AP accelerator. Our business is based out of CT, USA, with clients all over the country. We have a development center in Hyderabad, India
- As an early hire, I am part of the core Management team, responsible for back-end technology, hiring, and ensuring high availability at a 24/7 business
- I was the Lead Engineer & Architect for products such as YantraPlatform, YantraSign and ScreenVive. I was leading the team through all stages of development cycle. From feature planning, design, implementation and support
- Introduced Functional and Reactive Programming paradigms to the team and helped migrate to RxJava and RxJs
- Led the migration to a Micro Service Architecture and Kubernetes
 Deployments within the company, which vastly improved our deployment cycles
- Migrated from a bespoke auth server to RBAC based Keycloak for fine grained authentication and authorization, including support for OAuth2.0 and OpenID Connect for 3rd party authentication

- I led a team to setup & maintain a comprehensive DevOps pipeline using Bitbucket, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Vault, Prometheus, Grafana
- YantraPlatform: A bespoke IoT platform designed for media intensive applications such as Digital Signage and Kiosks. Allows for monitoring and pixel-level management of thousands of screens spread across the world. https://www.yantranet.com
- YantraSign: A Digital Signage solution that leverages the YantraPlatorm to deliver seamless control over content delivery, across a network of screens. https://yantrasign.com
- ScreenVive: Content as a Service for your Digital Screens. Access a variety of configurable content feeds ranging from news, entertainment, trivia etc to be used on your screens. https://screenvive.com

Tickscore Pvt. Ltd Co-Founder & Lead Backend Engineer January 2017 - April 2019 (2 years 4 months) Hyderabad Area, India

- An online service helping students prepare for the Civil Services Examination in India. Students could practise either online or using an Android App, against a well-curated set of questions and get detailed analytics on their progress.
- I designed and developed the backend services.

InMins Pvt. Ltd.
Co-Founder
January 2011 - March 2012 (1 year 3 months)
Hyderabad Area, India

- A food delivery app created long before mobile apps became prevalent. It was a web-based service, which catered to foodies in Hyderabad, India.
- I desinged and developed the customer-facing web app and an administration console, for managing daily operations.

DERI: Digital Enterprise Research Institute Research Associate August 2008 - September 2011 (3 years 2 months) Galway, Ireland

- Digi.me: An EU funded research project to develop an Intelligent Trustenhancing Store of a Users personal information sphere in digital and social environments.

- Nepomuk: A Social Semantic Desktop built on top of KDE which enables a deeper inter-connection of data from various applications using RDF other Semantic Web Technologies
- Publications: I co-authored 4 research papers and a journal in the field of NLP and Semantic Web
- Technologies Used: Java, Python, GWT, RDF, OWL, Research, Academic Writing

Data Management Group, University of Trento Research And Development Intern December 2007 - June 2008 (7 months) Trento Area, Italy

- Context based Word Similarity using Wikipedia: An EASTWeb funded research project exploring the use of Wikipedia for Semantic Analysis. I developed a Term Similarity module using page links, page content and category links within Wikipedia
- Technologies Used: Java, MySQL, XML, J2EE

Education

Indian Institute Of Information Technology
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology (2004 - 2008)

National University of Ireland, Galway (2008 - 2010)